### CHRISTOHER J SANDERS

(502) 377-8409 | Denver, CO 80221 | cjsand03@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/cj-sanders1986 | GitHub: github.com/EsotericZ Portfolio: https://esotericz.github.io/portfolio

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Junior Full Stack Web Developer making a career shift from mechanical engineering. Graduate of University of Denver Boot Camp with multi-year experience developing both personal and professional web applications independently. Engineering and management background helps to approach problems both strategically and effectively. Three years experience developing/maintaining an internal website and database alongside my daily job requirements.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS, GraphQL,

Python 3.X, Flask, Pandas

Databases: MySQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

#### **PROJECTS**

#### famYOUly | github.com/EsotericZ/famYOUly | https://evening-island-73261.herokuapp.com/login

- An interactive app that you can collaborate with your child's support network to post events, have a shared calendar, add todos and store vital information to share within your network.
- I was responsible for developing the framework, backend code, modules and calendar on the website. I was in charge of quality control and was the designated scrum master
- This application was built using NodeJS, HandlebarsJS, ExpressJS, MySQL, Sequelize, JQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

### Monarch Home | gitlab.com/Zanatos/mmhome

- Private webpage that runs on the local servers at Monarch Metal Manufacturing. Used to track
  all jobs in the system, store vital information, calculate bend deductions, monitor employee
  status and keep up to date material stock information.
- I have built, maintained and managed this project from the ground up and continue to make improvements to ensure accuracy and stability throughout the application's life.
- This application was built using Flask, SocketIO, SQLite, SQLalchemy, Bootstrap HTML, CSS

### **Automated Quoting Software | Private Github Repo**

- Developed and continually maintained an automated quotation software that takes a 3D CAD sheet metal model and gets all pertinent data for the part output into a dictionary. With this, the app calculates material usage, run times, shop operations and builds/exports the correct routing for the part/assembly for use in the company database.
- Rebuilding the front end to be a more dynamic and interactive experience with the user. Features include file upload, forms, modules and dynamic information handling.
- Collaboration with a partner to modify and implement FreeCAD software to get detailed information and run efficiently in the background.
- Application saves on average 5-10 minutes quoting time on simple parts, 2-5+ hours on complex assemblies within our company.
- This application was built using Flask, SocketIO, mySQL, FreeCAD, Bootstrap HTML, CSS

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# LEAD ENGINEER MONARCH METAL MANUFACTURING

SEPTEMBER 2013 - CURRENT DENVER, CO

I have been the lead engineer for the last eight years and responsible for managing three departments within the organization. I am tasked with keeping current and upcoming jobs on schedule and maintaining their accuracy as they travel through the shop. *Key Accomplishments:* 

- Created and maintained an internal website to track and handle all current and future job location and status as well as vital shop and office information.
- Developed a large-scale material rack that utilizes load cells to continually update the amount of material on hand at any given moment.
- Create and continually update our quoting software to match our changing capabilities

# VICE PRESIDENT COLORADO RACQUETBALL

2018 - CURRENT DENVER, CO

After six plus years volunteering at racquetball tournaments and charity events I was elected Vice President. On top of quarterly meetings with the United States Racquetball Association, I am responsible for hosting two multi-day statewide tournaments a year and developing new ideas for continued growth and improvement of the sport and it's players. *Key Accomplishments:* 

• After a year and a half halt to all indoor activities successfully hosted one of the first live events coming back from the global pandemic with no issues.

## LEAD ENGINEER HAFENDORFER MACHINE

MAY 2010 - JULY 2013 LOUISVILLE, KY

Head of Engineering and Quality Control departments. Utilized new techniques in programming and leadership to increase efficiency. Developed spreadsheets to track flow of items in the shop.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Boot Camp Certificate:** University of Denver, Denver, CO

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

**Master's of Mechanical Engineering:** University of Louisville, Louisville, KY A Five year year round program that consists of 14 semesters and three co-op internships. The program is accredited by the Engineering Accreditation Commission of ABET.